Register of the Boutros Boutros-Ghali papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Secretary-General of the United Nations File, 1981-2001 (Boxes 62-202)
  - Speeches and writings, 1991-1996 (Boxes 175-183)
    - "In Copenhagen, A New Kind of Summit," op-ed in Washington Times, 1995 February 6 (Box-folder 180: 16)
    - Introductory statement to the Forum on the Future of the United Nations, Vienna, 1995 March 1 (Box-folder 180: 17)
    - "The 25th Seminar Peacemaking and Peace-keeping for the Next Century," Vienna, 1995 March 2 (Box-folder 180: 18)
    - "Democracy, Media and the UN," Tenth Annual Conference, Columbia University, 1995 March 19 (Box-folder 180: 19)
    - "Managing the Peace-keeping Challenge," Yale University, 1995 March 21 (Box-folder 180: 20)
    - Message to the 20th Conference of the National High School Model United Nations, 1995 March 22 (Box-folder 180: 21)
    - Message of the Secretary-General to the World Federation of United Nations Associations' Fifth Regional Conference of United Nations Association in Asia and the Pacific, Dhaka, 1995 March 24-28 (Box-folder 180: 22)
    - Address to members of the New York Stock Exchange, 1995 April 5 (Box-folder 180: 23)
    - Remarks at the meeting to commemorate the 40th anniversary of the Bandung Afro-Asia Conference of 1955, Bandung, 1995 April 24 (Box-folder 180: 24)
    - "A Groatian Moment," typescript and printed copy, 1995 May (Box-folder 180: 25)
    - Remarks for the luncheon commemorating the 50th anniversary of the signing of the New York State Human Rights Law, New York, 1995 May 15 (Box-folder 180: 26)
    - Message on the occasion of the 75th anniversary of the American University in Cairo, Harvard Club, New York, 1995 May 18 (Box-folder 180: 27)
    - "Address at a reception hosted by the Foreign Minister of New Zealand H. E. Mr. Don McKinnon, under the auspices of the Institute for International Affairs and the United Nations Association of New Zealand,", 1995 May 1 (Box-folder 180: 28)
    - Foreword by the Secretary-General to the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences' book, "Pithy Speeches at the UN Forum,", 1995 May (Box-folder 181: 1)
    - "Toast at a lunch offered by the Prime Minister of New Zealand, H.E. Mr. James Bolger," Wellington, 1995 May 1 (Box-folder 181: 2)
    - "Allocutions du Secretaire General de L'Organisation des Nations Unies lors de la commemoration du cinquantième anniversaire de la victoire alliée," Moscow, 1995 May 9 (Box-folder 181: 3)
    - Concluding statement to the book One World, 1995 May 19 (Box-folder 181: 4)
    - Address to the annual dinner of the Foreign Policy Association, New York, 1995 June 19 (Box-folder 181: 5)
    - World Affairs Council speech, 1995 June 23 (Box-folder 181: 6)
    - Remarks, M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, San Francisco, 1995 June 24 (Box-folder 181: 7)
    - Remarks, NGO Forum, San Francisco, 1995 June 24 (Box-folder 181: 8)
    - Introductory statement to the Forum on the Reform and Renewal of the United Nations, 1995 June 24 (Box-folder 181: 9)
    - "Managing the United Nations: Mapping the Road Ahead," UNA/USA National Convention, San Francisco, 1995 June 25 (Box-folder 181: 10)
    - Message of the Secretary-General to the National Convention of the United Nations' Association of the United States of America, San Francisco, 1995 June 25-28 (Box-folder 181: 11)
    - Remarks at the Inter-Faith Service, Grace Cathedral, San Francisco, 1995 June 25 (Box-folder 181: 12)
    - Remarks for Charter Ceremony, San Francisco, 1995 June 26 (Box-folder 181: 13)
    - Remarks at dedication of United Nations Plaza, San Francisco, 1995 June 26 (Box-folder 181: 14)
    - Civic luncheon, San Francisco, 1995 June 26 (Box-folder 181: 15)
    - Remarks on reform at the Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC), Geneva, 1995 July 4 (Box-folder 181: 16)
    - Address at the Session of the Economic and Social Council, 1995 July 4 (Box-folder 181: 17)
    - Address for the Onassis Prize for International Understanding and Social Achievement, 1995 July 11 (Box-folder 181: 18)
    - Message for a publication to mark Indonesia's 50th independence anniversary, 1995 August (Box-folder 181: 19)
    - Address to the Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, 1995 September 4 (Box-folder 181: 20)
    - Introduction of Pope John Paul II, draft, 1995 October 5 (Box-folder 181: 21)
    - United Nations correspondents dinner talking points, 1995 October 27 (Box-folder 181: 22)
    - Opening remarks at UN Security Council, 1995 December 15 (Box-folder 181: 23)
    - Remarks at reception on the occasion of the 20th anniversary of the United Nations University and the launching of UNU research initiative, "The United Nations System in the 21st Century,", 1995 December 18 (Box-folder 181: 24)
    - Introduction to Brown Journal of World Affairs issue on UN Peacekeeping, 1996 (Box-folder 181: 25)
    - "Crisis at the UN: What's Going On?" New York Times op-ed, 1996 (Box-folder 181: 26)
    - Statement to the meeting of the Group of 77, 1996 January 22 (Box-folder 181: 27)
    - Luncheon with UN Security Council, 1996 January 26 (Box-folder 181: 28)
    - "Leadership and Conflict," Carnegie essay, 1996 January 30 (Box-folder 181: 29)
    - Statement to the General Assembly's High Level Group on the Financial Situation of the United Nations, 1996 February 6 (Box-folder 181: 30)
    - Toast at dinner in honor of participants in the United Nations and regional organizations second meeting, New York, 1996 February 15 (Box-folder 181: 31)
    - Speech book from visit to Brazil and Mexico, 1996 February 27-March 5 (Box-folder 182: 1-2)
    - Speech at ministry of foreign affairs, Mexico, 1996 March 4 (Box-folder 182: 3)
    - Speeches from visit to Seoul, South Korea, 1996 March-April (Box-folder 182: 4)
    - "Global Leadership After the Cold War," Foreign Affairs, 1996 March/April (Box-folder 182: 5-6)
    - Speeches of the Secretary-General in Asia, memoranda and notes, 1996 March (Box-folder 182: 7)
    - "The UN and Disarmament: Next Steps,", 1996 April (Box-folder 182: 8)
    - Speeches from visits to Tokyo, 1996 April (Box-folder 182: 9)
    - "The Land Mine Crisis: A Model of UN Leadership," Republic of Korea, 1996 April 1 (Box-folder 182: 10)
    - "Statement of the Secretary-General to the 8th Ministerial Meeting of the Standing Advisory Committee on Security Questions in Central Africa," Yaounde, Cameroon, 1996 April 18-19 (Box-folder 182: 11)
    - Remarks of the Secretary-General to United Nations staff, Johannesburg, 1996 April 26 (Box-folder 182: 12)
    - Address to UNCTAD-IX, 1996 April 27 (Box-folder 182: 13)
    - Remarks of the Secretary-General to United Nations staff, Nairobi, 1996 April 29 (Box-folder 182: 14)
    - "Security Council Reform," Tokyo, 1996 April (Box-folder 182: 15)
    - Speech at meeting/luncheon with chairs of major American institutions, 1996 May 8 (Box-folder 182: 16)
    - Opening remarks for CNN Forum, draft and memoranda, 1996 May 9 (Box-folder 182: 17)
    - "Discours du secretaire general de l'Organisation des Nations Unies à l'occasion de la conférence sur les réfugiés et personnes déplacées dans la communaute des état indépendants," Geneva, 1996 May 30 (Box-folder 182: 18)
    - "The Future of Peacekeeping," draft, 1996 August (Box-folder 182: 19)
    - Address to the Commemorative Meeting of the Movement of the Non-Aligned Countries on Its 35th Anniversary, New York, 1996 September 24 (Box-folder 182: 20)
    - Statements on United Nations Day, 1996 October (Box-folder 182: 21)
    - "Integration of Economies in Transition into the World Economy," Malente Symposium XI, 1996 October 17 (Box-folder 182: 22)
    - Toast at dinner given by the Foreign Minister of Germany, H. E. Mr. Klaus Kinkel, 1996 October 17 (Box-folder 182: 23)
    - Letters to the editor, New York Times, 1996 October (Box-folder 182: 24)
    - Speech at Overseas Club, 1996 October 19 (Box-folder 182: 25)
    - Statement to the World Youth Forum, Vienna, 1996 November 25-29 (Box-folder 182: 26)
    - Address to Department of Public Information (DPI) Human Rights Day Conference, New York, 1996 December 12 (Box-folder 182: 27)
    - Farewell statement, 1996 December 17 (Box-folder 182: 28)
    - Statement to the General Assembly, 1996 December 17 (Box-folder 183: 1)
    - Video address to the Yomiuri Shimbun Symposium, Tokyo, 1996 December 19 (Box-folder 183: 2)
    - An Agenda for Democratization, 1996
      - Summary, undated (Box-folder 183: 3)
      - Notes on drafts and correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 183: 4)
      - Note by Charles Hill and letters from Bruce Russett, Alfred Stepan, Robert A. Dahl, Larry Diamond, David Hamburg, Yevgeny Primakov, and Cyrus Vance, 1996 (Box-folder 183: 5)
      - Draft, 1996 January 12 (Box-folder 183: 6)
      - "Supplement to Reports A/50/332 and A/51/512 on Democratization,", 1996 December 17 (Box-folder 183: 7-8)
        Scope and Contents
      - Drafts, notes, and correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 183: 9)
      - Rosario Green memorandum criticizing early draft, 1997 (Box-folder 183: 10)
      - Bruce Russett correspondence, 1997 (Box-folder 183: 11)
      - Review of An Agenda for Peace, An Agenda for Development, and An Agenda for Democratization by Bruce Russett, 1997 June (Box-folder 183: 12)
    - Preface to the "Blue Book" on Yugoslavia, 1996 December 31 (Box-folder 183: 13)
  - Tributes, 1996 (Box-folder 183: 14)
  - Trips and media reports (Boxes 184-200)
    Binders containing clippings, briefing books, speeches, and press releases related to the Secretary-General's official visits to countries. See also: Clippings dossiers and Press releases for related materials.
    - Trips
      - 1992-1993
        - Colombia, 1992 February (Box-folder 184: 1)
        - India, China, Cambodia, 1992 April (Box-folder 184: 2)
        - Nigeria, 1992 June (Box-folder 184: 3)
        - Nicaragua, 1992 December (Box-folder 184: 4)
        - Paris, Germany, Cairo, Addis Ababa, Somalia, Sarajevo, Geneva, 1992 December 24-1993 January 15 (Box-folder 184: 5)
        - Belgium, Thailand, Rome, Phnom Penh, London, Vietnam, 1993 April 2-24 (Box-folder 184: 6, Box-folder 185: 1)
        - Austria, Ukraine, Egypt, Switzerland, 1993 June-July (Box-folder 185: 2)
          Speeches.
        - Europe and Africa, October 13-27 (Box-folder 185: 3)
          Chronological record of visit.
      - 1994
        - Moscow, Belarus, Germany, Geneva, Spain, March-April (Box-folder 185: 4)
        - Argentina, March 12-15 (Box-folder 185: 5)
        - Japan, September 11-14 (Box-folder 186: 1-2)
        - Azerbaijan, October 29-31 (Box-folder 186: 3)
      - 1995
        - Davos, Switzerland, January 7-27 (Box-folder 186: 4)
        - Austria and Denmark, February 24-March 13 (Box-folder 186: 5)
        - Central America and Haiti, March 30-April 3 (Box-folder 186: 6-7)
        - Indonesia, Australia, New Zealand, Fiji, Russia, France, April 19-May 13 (Box-folder 187: 1-2)
        - Switzerland, Greece, Cairo, Uganda, Rwanda, Angola, Zaire, Burundi, Addis Ababa, London, June 28-July 22 (Box-folder 187: 3-4)
        - Burundi, July (Box-folder 187: 5)
        - Poland and Strasbourg, November 9-14 (Box-folder 188: 1)
          Speech book.
        - Canada, November 21-23 (Box-folder 188: 2)
        - Ghana, Liberia, Benin, Cote d'Ivoire, London, Paris, November 26-December 14 (Box-folder 188: 3-5)
        - Australia, December (Box-folder 188: 6)
      - 1996
        - Kuwait, Yemen, Eritrea, Egypt, Italy, United Kingdom, France, 1995 December 25-1996 January 17 (Box-folder 188: 7, Box-folder 189: 1-2)
          Includes briefing books.
        - Brazil and Mexico, February 26-March 1 (Box-folder 189: 3-4)
        - Sharm El Skeikh; Geneva, France, China, Korea, Japan, March 18-April 7 (Box-folder 190: 1-2)
        - South Africa and Kenya, April 25-29 (Box-folder 190: 3)
        - South Africa, Kenya, France, April 25-May 2 (Box-folder 191: 1)
        - Russian Federation, May 13-18 (Box-folder 191: 2)
          Includes speeches.
        - Moscow, May 14-18 (Box-folder 191: 3)
        - Canada, May 25 (Box-folder 191: 4)
        - Turkey, May 28-June 5 (Box-folder 191: 5-6)
        - Germany, June 18-22 (Box-folder 192: 1)
        - Turkey, Bonn, London, Geneva, Lyon, Cameroon, June-July (Box-folder 192: 2-3)
        - Organization of African Unity (OAU) Summit Meeting in Yaoundé, Cameroon, July (Box-folder 192: 4)
        - Guatemala, December 28-29 (Box-folder 192: 5)
      - Programs from official visits of the Secretary-General, 1992-1996 and undated (Box-folder 193: 1-5)
      - Miscellaneous invitations and menus, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 194: 1)
    - Media reports (Boxes 194-200)
      - 1992-1993
        - Geneva, Paris, Bonn, Paris, 1992 December 24-1993 January 17 (Box-folder 194: 2)
        - Italy, San Marino, Belgium, 1993 April 13-24 (Box-folder 194: 3)
        - Geneva and Paris, 1993 August 30-September 7 (Box-folder 194: 4)
        - Paris, Africa, London, 1993 October 13-26 (Box-folder 194: 5-6)
      - 1994
        - Paris, Geneva, The Hague, Paris, January 7-24 (Box-folder 195: 1)
        - Europe, April 1-17 (Box-folder 195: 2)
        - Europe, May 1-6 (Box-folder 195: 3)
        - Geneva, Tunis, Geneva, June 5-15 (Box-folder 196: 1-2)
        - Europe, October 22-November 8 (Box-folder 196: 3-5)
      - 1995
        - Paris, Geneva, Finland, Sweden, Denmark, Germany, Switzerland (Davos and Geneva), January 6-27 (Box-folder 197: 1-3)
        - Vienna and Copenhagen, February 24-March 13 (Box-folder 197: 4-6)
        - Indonesia, Australia, New Zealand, Fiji, April 21-May 6 (Box-folder 198: 1-3)
        - Geneva, Athens, Africa, Geneva, June 29-July 20 (Box-folder 198: 4-5, Box-folder 199: 1)
        - Geneva, Poland, Strasbourg, November 7-15 (Box-folder 199: 2)
        - Europe and West Africa, November 25-December 14 (Box-folder 199: 3)
      - 1996
        - Geneva, March 15-20 (Box-folder 200: 1)
        - Germany, June 19-22 (Box-folder 200: 2)
        - Organization of African Unity (OAU) Summit, Yaoundé, Cameroon, July 7-10 (Box-folder 200: 3)
        - Germany (Hamburg and Lubeck), October 16-19 (Box-folder 200: 4)
        - Rome, Italy, November 10-13 (Box-folder 200: 5)
  - Writings by others (Box 201)
    - Aimé, Jean-Claude, 1996 (Box-folder 201: 1)
    - Chopra, Jarat, 1996 (Box-folder 201: 2)
    - de Cuellar, Javier Pérez, 1993 (Box-folder 201: 3)
    - Deng, Francis Mading, undated (Box-folder 201: 4)
    - Elaraby, Nabil, undated (Box-folder 201: 5)
    - Farouk, Princess Fadila, undated (Box-folder 201: 6)
    - Finkel, Stephen, 1993 (Box-folder 201: 7)
    - Franck, Thomas M., undated (Box-folder 201: 8)
    - Friedrich, Carl J., undated (Box-folder 201: 9)
    - Goulding, Marrack, 1993 (Box-folder 201: 10)
    - Hill, Emily B., 1994 (Box-folder 201: 11)
    - Homer-Dixon, Thomas, 1994 (Box-folder 201: 12)
    - Kennedy, Paul and Bruce Russett, undated (Box-folder 201: 13)
    - Lombardo, Caroline, 1997 (Box-folder 201: 14)
    - Pisani, Edgard, undated (Box-folder 201: 15)
    - Roberts, Adam, 1993, 1995 (Box-folder 201: 16)
    - Ruggie, John Gerard, 1994 (Box-folder 201: 17)
    - Spencer, Samia I., 1993 (Box-folder 201: 18)
    - "America's Role in World Affairs and the Future of the United Nations,", 1995 (Box-folder 201: 19)
    - Remarks of Peter D. Trooboff, Hague Academy of International Law, 1993 November 1 (Box-folder 201: 20)
    - "United Nations Reform: Looking Ahead After Fifty Years,", 1994 (Box-folder 201: 21)
    - Speech by Jesse Jackson, 1992 (Box-folder 201: 22)
      Signed by Jackson with a note to Boutros-Ghali.
  - Miscellany (Box 202)
    - Postcards and souvenir map of the Nile, undated (Box-folder 202: 1)
    - Sketches, undated (Box-folder 202: 2)
    - United Nations bumper sticker, undated (Box-folder 202: 3)
    - Media strategy and interview guides, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 202; 4)
    - Memorandum presented to the Secretary-General from NGO's of Jammu and Kashmir, 1994 September (Box-folder 202: 5)
    - Memorandum presented to the Secretary-General from the All Parties Hurriet Conference, 1994 (Box-folder 202: 6)
    - Asian-African Conference communique, 1995 April (Box-folder 202: 7)
    - The Egypt Trust asset management portfolio, 1996 (Box-folder 202: 8)
- Charles Hill Advising and Projects File, 1969-2001 (Boxes 203-238)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, memoranda, speeches, writings, reports, and printed matter relating to the work of the Secretary-General and Charles Hill's role as his policy advisor. Also includes drafts and research materials for the publication of Papers of the Secretary-General, Boutros Boutros-Ghali. Arranged alphabetically by physical form, and chronologically or alphabetically thereunder.
  - General
    - Notes on themes found in Boutros-Ghali's writings, undated (Box-folder 203: 1)
    - Requests for UN documents, 1996 (Box-folder 203: 2)
    - Miscellaneous office notes and memoranda, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 203: 3)
  - Biographical statement, undated (Box-folder 203: 4)
  - Briefing book given to Boutros-Ghali after his election to Secretary General, 1991 (Box-folder 203: 5)
  - Change in the secretariat, notes and correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 203: 6)
  - Clippings, bound volumes, 1992-1996
    - Washington Post series on "Waste and Management in the UN,", 1992 September (Box-folder 203: 7)
    - "Bosnia, NATO, General Cot," binder of clippings (photocopies), 1994 (Box-folder 203: 8-10, Box-folder 204: 1)
    - Re-election campaign, 1996 (Box-folder 204: 2)
  - Code cables and cryptofax transmissions, photocopies, 1992-1995 (Boxes 164-165)
    Photocopies of cables sent to the Secretary General.
    - United Nations Offices, New York and Geneva, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 204: 3)
    - International Conference on the Former Yugoslavia, 1992, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 204: 4-5)
    - MINUGUA (United Nations Verification Mission in Guatemala), 1995 (Box-folder 204: 6)
    - MINUSAL (United Nations Mission in El Salvador), 1995 (Box-folder 204: 7)
    - MINURSO (United Nations Mission for the Referendum in Western Sahara), 1995 (Box-folder 204: 8)
    - ONUMOZ (United Nations Operations in Mozambique), 1994 (Box-folder 204: 9)
    - ONUSAL (United Nations Observer Mission in El Salvador), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 204: 10)
    - OSGAP (Office of the Secretary General in Afghanistan and Pakistan), 1994 (Box-folder 204: 11)
    - UNAVEM II (United Nations Angola Verification Mission), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 204: 12)
    - UNAVEM III (United Nations Angola Verification Mission), 1995 (Box-folder 205: 1)
    - UNAMIR - MINUAR (Assistance Mission for Rwanda), 1994 (Box-folder 205: 2)
    - UNOSOM (United Nations Operations in Somalia), 1992 (Box-folder 205: 3)
    - UNOSOM II (United Nations Operations in Somalia), 1994 (Box-folder 205: 4)
    - UNPROFOR (United Nations Protective Force), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 205: 5-6)
  - Correspondence regarding drafts and publication of Egypt's Road to Jerusalem, Unvanquished, and The Papers of the Secretary General, Boutros Boutros-Ghali, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 205: 7-8)
  - Finances and budget documents (Joseph E. Connor), 1993-1996
    - Outstanding contributions to the regular budget and peacekeeping operations, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 205: 9-10)
    - Statements, talking points, and presentations on the financial situation at the UN, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 205: 11-14)
    - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, 1996 February 2 (Box-folder 205: 15)
  - Notes, 1992-1997
    - Notes on meeting with Boutros Boutros-Ghali to agree on their relationship at the UN, 1992 May (Box-folder 206: 1)
    - Notes and research materials from talks on the UN, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 206: 2)
      Includes draft of statement by Javier Perez de Cuellar, Zurich, Switzerland, 1993 May 10.
    - Notes and memorandum on U.S. and UN and Somalia, 1993 October (Box-folder 206: 3)
    - Notebook (diary) on UN events, 1996 March-December (Box-folder 206: 4)
      Contains daily reflections on events surrounding U.S.-UN relations and other policy matters.
    - Notes, 1996 April-June (Box-folder 206: 5)
    - Notebook (diary) on UN events, 1996 December-1997 March (Box-folder 206: 6)
    - Notes on Marrack I. Goulding discussion of the UN during Boutros-Ghali's term as secretary general, 1997 March (Box-folder 206: 7)
    - Notes, 1997 August (Box-folder 206: 8)
  - Policy notes, talking points, and recommendations, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 206: 9-10)
    Includes notes and letters to the Secretary General's chief of staff, Jean Claude Aimé, speech drafts, and briefing notes for Boutros-Ghali's meeting with President Bill Clinton on February 23, 1993. Also includes notes relating to policy planning unit.
  - "S-G Special" file, clippings, speeches, notes, and correspondence, 1992-1996
    - 1992-1994 (Box-folder 207: 1)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 207: 2-3)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 207: 4)
  - Subject, policy and research file, 1969-2001 (Boxes 207-223)
    Charles Hill's original file titles were used, when available.
    - Africa, 1992-1996
      - General, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 207: 5)
      - Counter-genocide of Hutu refugees in Zaire, bulletin and clipping, 1996 (Box-folder 207: 6)
      - The UN in Africa, speech drafts and clippings, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 207: 7)
    - AIDS, UN pamphlet, 1995 (Box-folder 207: 8)
    - Albright, Madeleine, 1993-1997
      - General, clippings, speeches, and memoranda, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 207: 9)
      - Eastern Slavonia debate, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 207: 10)
      - Press leak, 1996 November (Box-folder 207: 11)
    - American foreign policy, Charles Hill policy notes to Boutros Boutros-Ghali, 1993 November (Box-folder 207: 12)
    - Angola, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 207: 13)
    - Annan, Kofi, appointment as Secretary General of the United Nations, 1996 (Box-folder 207: 14)
    - Armenia, press conference information, 1993 (Box-folder 207: 15)
    - Armenian genocide, documentation of U.S. request to Wacyf Boutros-Ghali, 1924 February 15, 1992 (Box-folder 207: 16)
    - Blue Books update, 1996 October (Box-folder 208: 1)
      Includes photographs from book fairs.
    - Bosnia (former Yugoslavia)
      - General
        - 1992 (Box-folder 208: 2)
        - 1993 (Box-folder 208: 3)
        - 1994 (Box-folder 208: 4-5)
        - 1995 (Box-folder 208: 6)
        - 1996 (Box-folder 208: 7)
        - Chronology and notes by Charles Hill, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 208: 8)
        - Notebook of articles and documents compiled by Charles Hill, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 208: 9-10)
      - Book notes, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 208: 11)
      - Air strikes, 1993-1995
        - Controversy, 1995 (Box-folder 208: 12)
        - Debate, 1994 (Box-folder 208: 13-14)
        - Decisions (Gorazde), 1995 July-August (Box-folder 208: 15)
        - Decisions (Sarajevo), 1994 January-February (Box-folder 209: 1)
        - "Draft report of the Secretary General Pursuant to Security Council Resolutions 982 (1995) and 987 (1995)" and related clippings (Box-folder 209: 2)
        - "Proposed Airdrop Operation in Bosnia and the President's Meeting with UN Secretary General," memorandum, undated (Box-folder 209: 3)
        - "Use of Air Power in Support of UNPROFOR in Bosnia and Herzegovina," memorandum, undated (Box-folder 209: 4)
      - Dayton Peace Accords, 1995 (Box-folder 209: 5-7)
        Includes copy of "Dayton Agreement on Implementing the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina," 1995 November 10.
      - Genocide, 1993 (Box-folder 209: 8)
      - Heavy weapons
        - London agreement, 1992 (Box-folder 209: 9)
          Includes notes from Alvara de Soto and Marrack Goulding.
        - General Assembly Resolution A/46/L.76, 1992 August (Box-folder 209: 10)
          Includes handwritten notes by Boutros Boutros-Ghali.